<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
<string name="title8">Hazrat Abdul Rehman (R.A)</string>
    <string name="detail8">
        His parents were both from the Zuhra clan of the Quraysh tribe in Mecca. His father was Awf ibn Abd-Awf and his mother was al-Shifaa bint Awf.
His original name was Abdu Amru ("servant of Amru"). It was Muhammad who renamed him Abd al-Rahman ("servant of the Most Merciful").It is also said that his original name was Abdul Kaaba. His name has also been transliterated as Abdel Rahman Ibn Auf.
Abu Bakr spoke to Abd al-Rahman about Islam, then invited him to meet Muhammad, who heard his declaration of faith and taught him the Islamic prayers. This was before the Muslims had entered the house of Al-Arqam; Abd al-Rahman was one of the first eight men to accept Islam. \n\n
From about 614 the pagan Quraysh in Mecca showed their enmity to all those who followed the apostle; every clan which contained Muslims was attacked. The usual threat to Muslim merchants was: "We will boycott your goods and reduce you to beggary."
Abd al-Rahman was one of a pioneering party of fifteen Muslims who emigrated to Abyssinia in 615. Other Muslims joined them later, forming a group of over a hundred. "They were safely ensconced there and grateful for the protection of the Negus; could serve Allah without fear, and the Negus had shown them every hospitality." In late 619 or early 620 "they heard that the Meccans had accepted Islam." This probably refers to the Gharaniq episode. Abd al-Rahman was one of forty who "set out for the homeland. But when they got near Mecca they learned that the report was false, so that they entered the town under the protection of a citizen or by stealth."\n\n
Abd al-Rahman was friends with Umayyah ibn Khalaf, a stern opponent of Islam. When Abd al-Rahman emigrated to Medina, the two reached a written agreement, according to which Abd al-Rahman was to protect Umayyah property and family in Medina, while Umayyah would protect Abd al-Rahman in Mecca. When Abd al-Rahman wanted to sign the document, Umayyah protested, saying "I do not know Ar-Rahman" and requested that the pre-Islamic name "Abdu Amr" should be used, to which Abd al-Rahman agreed.\n\n
The two met again in the Battle of Badr in March 624.
A hadith attributed to Abd-al-Rahman ibn Awf reports.\n\n
On the day (of the battle) of Badr, when all the people went to sleep, I went up the hill to protect him. Bilal(1) saw him (i.e. Umaiya) and went to a gathering of Ansar and said, "(Here is) Umaiya bin Khalaf! Woe to me if he escapes!" \n\nSo, a group of Ansar went out with Bilal to follow us (Abdur-Rahman and Umaiya). Being afraid that they would catch us, I left Umaiya son for them to keep them busy but the Ansar killed the son and insisted on following us. Umaiya was a fat man, and when they approached us, I told him to kneel down, and he knelt, and I laid myself on him to protect him, but the Ansar killed him by passing their swords underneath me, and one of them injured my foot with his sword. (The sub narrator said, " Abdur-Rahman used to show us the trace of the wound on the back of his foot.")
Sunnis tend to view this as Sahih and have included it in Sahih Bukhari


    </string>
</resources>