<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="title1">Hazrat Abu Bakkar Siddique (R.A)</string>
<string name="detail1">
    Abu Bakr was born in Mecca some time in 573 CE,
    to a rich family in the Banu Taym tribe of the Quraysh tribal
    confederacy. His father name was Uthman and given the laqab Abu Quhafa,
    and his mother was Salma bint Sakhar who was given the laqab of Umm ul-Khair.
    A story is preserved that once when he was a child, his father took him to
    the Kaaba, and asked him to pray before the idols. His father went away to attend
    to some other business, and Abu Bakr was left alone.
    Addressing an idol, Abu Bakr said "O my God,\n\nI am in need of beautiful clothes; bestow them on me".
    The idol remained indifferent.
    Then he addressed another idol, saying,
    "O God, give me some delicious food. See that I am so hungry". The idol remained cold.
    That exhausted the patience of young Abu Bakr. He lifted a stone,
    and, addressing an idol, said,
    "Here I am aiming a stone
    \n\nif you are a god protect yourself".
    Abu Bakr hurled the stone at the idol and
    left the Kaaba Regardless, it recorded that prior to
    converting to Islam, Abu Bakr practised as a hanif and never worshipped idols.
     On his return from a business trip in Yemen, friends informed him that in his absence, Muhammad had declared himself the Messenger of God and proclaimed a new religion.\n The historian Al-Tabari, in his Tarikh al-Tabari, quotes from Muhammad ibn Saad ibn Abi Waqqas, who said:

I asked my father whether Abu Bakr was the first of the Muslims. He said, No, more than
    fifty people embraced Islam before Abu Bakr; but he was superior to us as a Muslim.
    And Umar ibn Khattab had embraced Islam after forty-five men and twenty-one women. As for
    the foremost one in the matter of Islam and faith, it was Ali ibn Abi Talib.\n\n
 In 622, on the invitation of the Muslims of Medina, Muhammad ordered Muslims to
    migrate to Medina. The migration began in batches. Ali was the last to remain in Mecca,
    entrusted with responsibility for settling any loans the Muslims had taken out, and
    famously slept in the bed of Muhammad when the Quraysh, led by Ikrima, attempted to murder
    Muhammad as he slept. Meanwhile, Abu Bakr accompanied Muhammad to Medina. Due to the danger
    posed by the Quraysh, they did not take the road, but moved in the opposite direction, taking
    refuge in a cave in Jabal Thawr, some five miles south of Mecca. Abdullah ibn Abi Bakr, the
    son of Abu Bakr, would listen to the plans and discussions of the Quraysh, and at night he
    would carry the news to the fugitives in the cave. Asma bint Abi Bakr, the daughter of Abu Bakr,
    brought them meals every day.Aamir, a servant of Abu Bakr, would bring a flock of goats
    to the mouth of the cave every night, where they were milked. The Quraysh sent search parties
    in all directions. One party came close to the entrance to the cave, but was unable to see them.
    Due to this, Quran verse 9:40 was revealed. Aisha, Abu Said al-Khudri and Abdullah ibn Abbas
    in interpreting this verse said that Abu Bakr was the companion who stayed with Muhammad
    in the cave.\n\n

After staying at the cave for three days and three nights, Abu Bakr and Muhammad proceed to
    Medina, staying for some time at Quba, a suburb of Medina.
    On 23 August 634, Abu Bakr fell sick and did not recover. He developed high fever and was
    confined to bed. His illness was prolonged, and when his condition worsened, he felt that
    his end was near. Realising this, he sent for Ali and requested him to perform his ghusl
    since Ali had also done it for Muhammad.\n\n
    Abu Bakr felt that he should nominate his successor so that the issue should not be a
    cause of dissension among the Muslims after his death, though there was already
    controversy over Ali not having been appointed. He appointed Umar for this role after
    discussing the matter with some companions. Some of them favoured the nomination and
    others disliked it, due to the tough nature of Umar.\n\n
    Abu Bakr thus dictated his last testament to Uthman ibn Affan as follows:

In the name of Most Merciful God. This is the last will and testament
    of Abu Bakr bin Abu Quhafa, when he is in
    the last hour of the world, and the first of the next;
    an hour in which the infidel must believe, the wicked be
    convinced of their evil ways, I nominate Umar bin al Khattab as my successor. Therefore,
    hear to him and obey him. If he acts right, confirm his actions.
    My intentions are good, but I cannot see the future results. However,
    those who do ill shall render themselves liable to severe account hereafter. Fare you well.
    May you be ever attended by the Divine favor of blessing.
</string>
</resources>