<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="title10">Hazrat Saeed (R.A)</string>
    <string name="detail10">
        Saeed became a Muslim not later than 614.
His wife Fatima was also an early convert. At first they kept their faith secret because Fatima brother Umar was a prominent persecutor of Muslims. Khabbab ibn al-Aratt often visited their house and read the Quran to Fatima.\n\n
One day Umar entered their house while Khabbab was reading and demanded to know what the "balderdash" was. When they denied that anything had been read, Umar seized Saeed and knocked him to the floor. Fatima stood up to defend her husband, and Umar hit her so hard that she bled. The couple admitted that they were Muslims. At the sight of the blood, Umar was sorry for what he had done, and asked to see what they had been reading. It was Ta-Ha, later to become the twentieth Surah of the Quran. Impressed by the beauty of the words, Umar decided to become a Muslim
Saeed joined the general emigration to Medina in 622 and at first lodged in the house of Rifa ibn Abdul-Mundhir. He was made the brother in Islam of Rafi ibn Malik of the Zurayq clan but an alternative tradition names his brother in Islam as Talha ibn Ubaydallah.\n\n
Saeed and Talha missed the Battle of Badr because Muhammad sent them ahead as scouts to report on the movements of Abu Sufyan caravan. When they heard that they had missed the caravan, they returned to Medina, only to find that Muhammad and his army had already reached Badr. They set out for Badr and met the returning victorious army at Turban. However, Muhammad gave them a share of the plunder as if they had been present.\n\n
Saeed participated in all the other battles in which Muhammad personally fought.
He served as Muhammad secretary and recorded the verses of the Quran.
He died in 671 AD (51 AH) during the reign of Muawiyah  at al-Aqiq. His body was carried back to Medina and buried there by Saeed ibn Abi Waqqas and Abdullah ibn Umar.
Saeed said that Muhammad once guaranteed Paradise to ten men who were then present and named nine of them. Then he hinted that the tenth man had been himself. This story of the Ten Promised Paradise was corroborated by another of the Ten, Abd al-Rahman ibn Awf.


    </string>
</resources>