<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="title5">Hazrat Talha (R.A)</string>
    <string name="detail5">
        Talhah was born c.594, the son of Ubaydallah ibn Uthman of the Taym clan of the Quraysh tribe in Mecca. His mother, al-Saaba bint Abdullah, was from the Hadram tribe.
He is described as a dark-skinned man with a lot of wavy hair, a handsome face and a narrow nose. He liked to wear saffron-dyed clothes and musk. He walked swiftly and, when nervous, he would toy with his ring, which was of gold and set with a ruby.
Talhah was a successful cloth-merchant who eventually left an estate estimated at 30 million dirhams.
In 612 his kinsman Abu Bakr took him to visit Muhammad, and Talhah became a Muslim. He was said to have been one of the first eight converts.\n\n
During the persecution of the Muslims in 614-616, Nawfal ibn Khuwaylid tied Talhah to Abu Bakr and left them roped together. Nobody from the Taym clan came to help.  Thereafter they were known as "the Two Tied Together".
In the third week of July 632, Medina faced an imminent invasion by the apostate forces of Tulayha, a self-proclaimed prophet. Abu Bakr scraped together an army mainly from the Hashim clan (Muhammad), appointing Talhah, Ali ibn Abi Talib and Zubayr ibn al-Awam as Commanders of one-third of the newly organised force each. However, they did not face any combat scenaria during the Ridda Wars.\n\n
The Battle of the Camel was fought between Ali on one side and Aisha, Talhah and Zubayr on the other on 10 December 656. During the battle, Marwan ibn al-Hakam, who was fighting on the same side as Aisha, shot Talhah in the thigh. Marwan commented, "After this I will never again seek a killer of Uthman." Talhah hugged his horse and galloped off the battle-field. He lay down using a stone as a pillow, while the auxiliaries tried to staunch the blood-flow. Whenever they stopped pressing, the bleeding resumed. In the end Talhah said, "Stop it. This is an arrow sent by God." He died of this injury, aged 64.
According to a Sunni hadith, Muhammad named Talhah among the Ten Promised Paradise   al-Ashara al-Mubasharūn bi-l-Janna).
The tomb of Talha ibn Ubaydullah is located in Basra, Iraq. The tomb is located a large mosque with modern architecture. The grave itself is under the cenotaph under the dome, which is built in a similar style to the cenotaph of Anas Ibn Malik.


    </string>
</resources>