<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="title3">Hazrat Usman (R.A)</string>
    <string name="detail3">
        Uthman was born to Affan ibn Abi al-As, of the Umayya, and to Arwa bint Kurayz, of the Abdshams, both wealthy clans of the Quraysh tribe in Mecca. Arwas mother was Umm Hakim bint Abdul Muttalib, making Arwa the first cousin of Muhammad and Uthman his first cousin son. Uthman had one sister, Amina.\n\n

Uthman was born in Taif. The exact date is disputed: both 576 and 583 are indicated. He is listed as one of the 22 Meccans "at the dawn of Islam" who knew how to write.
        His father, Affan, died at a young age while travelling abroad, leaving Uthman with a large inheritance. He became a merchant like his father, and his business flourished, making him one of the richest men among the Quraysh.
        On returning from a business trip to Syria in 611, Uthman learned of Muhammad declared mission. After a discussion with Abu Bakr, Uthman decided to convert to Islam, and Abu Bakr brought him to Muhammad to declare his faith.\n\n Uthman thus became one of the earliest converts to Islam, following Ali, Zayd, Abu Bakr and a few others. His conversion to Islam angered his clan, the Banu Ummayyah, who strongly opposed Muhammad teachings.

    Uthman had a reputation of favouring family members. One way he displayed this was his habit of splitting war booty among his relatives to the exclusion of the combatants.During the Invasion of Hamra al-Asad a Meccan spy, Muawiyah bin Al Mugheerah, the cousin of Uthman ibn Affan, had been captured. According to the Muslim scholar Safiur Rahman Mubarakpuri, Uthman gave him shelter after getting permission from Muhammad, and Muhammad told him that if he was caught again after 3 days he would be executed.\n\n As such, Muawiyah was given a grace period of three days and arranged a camel and provisions for his return journey to Mecca. Uthman departed with Muhammad for Hamra-al-Asad, and Muawiyah overstayed his grace.\n\n Though he fled by the time the army returned, Muhammad ordered his pursuit and execution.\n\n
Umar, on his deathbed formed a committee of six people to choose the next caliph from amongst themselves. This committee was:
\n\n
Ali\n
Uthman ibn Affan\n
Abdur Rahman bin Awf\n
Sa`d ibn Abi Waqqas\n
Al-Zubayr\n
Talhah\n
Umar asked that, after his death, the committee reach a final decision within three days, and the next caliph should take the oath of office on the fourth day. If Talhah joined the committee within this period, he was to take part in the deliberations, but if he did not return to Medina within this period, the other members of the committee could proceed with the decision. Abdur Rahman bin Awf withdrew his eligibility to be appointed as caliph in order to act as a moderator and began his task by interviewing every member of the committee separately. He asked them for whom they would cast their vote. When Ali was asked, he did reply. When Uthman was asked, he voted for Ali, Zubayr said for Ali or Uthman and Saad said for Uthman.\n\n

Uthman was a rich merchant who used his wealth to support Islam yet at no time before his caliphate had he displayed any qualities of leadership or actually led an army. But despite this, according to Wilferd Madelung, he was chosen by the electors as the only strong counter candidate to Ali as he alone could to some extent rival Ali close kinship ties with the Prophet.
    </string>
</resources>