<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="title6">Hazrat Zubair ibn-e-Awan (R.A)</string>
    <string name="detail6">His father was Al-Awam ibn Khuwaylid of the Asad clan of the Quraysh tribe, making Al-Zubayr a nephew of Khadijah. His mother was Muhammad aunt, Safiyyah bint Abd al-Muttalib, hence Al-Zubayr was Muhammad first cousin. He had two brothers, Saib and Abdul Kaaba; a maternal brother, Safi ibn Al-Harith, who was from the Umayya clan; and several paternal siblings, including Hind bint Al-Awwam, a wife of Zayd ibn Haritha.
While he was still a boy, Al-Zubayr fought an adult man and beat him up so fiercely that the man hand was broken. Safiya, who was pregnant at the time, had to carry the man home. When the passers-by asked what had happened, she told them, "He fought Al-Zubayr. Did you find Al-Zubayr soft like cheese or dates or full of brass?" That when they knew that he would grow up to be strong during war.\n\n
Al-Awam died while Al-Zubayr was still young. His mother used to beat him severely. When it was said to her, "You have killed him! You have wrenched his heart. Will you destroy the boy?" she replied, "I beat him so that he will be intelligent and will be bold in the battle."
Al-Zubayr is described as of medium height, lean, dark-complexioned and hairy, though with a thin beard. His hair hung down to his shoulders, and he did not dye it after it turned white.
Al-Zubayr was one of the first five men to accept Islam under the influence of Abu Bakr, and is said to have been the fourth or fifth adult male convert.\n\n
He was one of the first fifteen emigrants to Abyssinia in 615, and he returned there in 616. While he was in Abyssinia, a rebellion against the Negus (King) broke out. The Negus met the rebels on the banks of the Nile. The Muslims, greatly worried about losing their protector, delegated Al-Zubayr to be their news-bearer. Helped by an inflated waterskin, he swam down the Nile until he reached the point where the battle was being fought. He watched until the Negus had defeated the rebels, then swam back to the Muslims. He ran up waving his clothes and announced, "Hurrah, the Negus has conquered and God has destroyed his enemies and established him in his land!" The Muslims rejoiced.
Al-Zubayr was among those who returned to Mecca in 619 because they heard that the Meccans had converted to Islam. "But when they got near to Mecca, they learned that the report was false, so that they entered the town under the protection of a citizen or by stealth. However, Al-Zubayr did not name his protector.
Al-Zubayr joined the general emigration to Medina in 622. At first he lodged with Al-Mundhir ibn Muhammad. It is disputed who became Al-Zubayr "brother" in Islam: variant traditions name Abdullah ibn Masood, Talha ibn Ubaydullah, Kaab ibn Malik and Salama ibn Salama. Muhammad gave him a large plot of land to build his house and a grant of some palm trees. In 625 Al-Zubayr was given more palm trees from the land of the expelled Nadir tribe.\n\n
At the Battle of Uhud he volunteered to take up Muhammad sword "with its right," which was to "smite the enemy with it until it bends," and was "much mortified" when Muhammad rejected his offer. He was standing so close to the fleeing Meccan women that he could see Hind bint Utbah anklets. But it was at that point that the battle turned; Al-Zubayr was one of the handful of men who stood beside Muhammad when the Muslims in their turn fled and who accompanied him to the glen. "He was firm with him in the Battle of Uhud and he gave him allegiance to the death.
In his will Al-Zubayr had left a house for all of his divorced daughters.He left a third of his property in bequests and instructed his son Abdullah to sell the rest of his property to pay off his debts, invoking Allah if any could not be paid. Abdullah found that the debts amounted to 1,200,000, presumably in dirhams. Although Abdullah went to some trouble to settle all the debts, Al-Zubayr four widows eventually inherited 1,100,000 each, leaving over 30,000,000 to be divided among his children.
Al-Zubayr ibn Al-Awam was one of the ten Muslims to whom Muhammad guaranteed Paradise while they were still alive.

</string>
</resources>